Guide to the Peter E. Palmquist Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- Publications and Publicity, 1960-2003; Series II; 5.3 linear feet (19 boxes)
  - Publications
    - Palmquist, Peter E. "Abbie E. Cardozo: Making it in a Man's World." The Humboldt Historian 39, no. 6 (1991): 24-25. (Box 50)
    - Palmquist, Peter E."Silver Plates on a Golden Shore: "The Real Thing Itself" in John Wood, America and the Daguerreotype (Iowa City: University of Iowa Press, 1991), 134-158. (Box 50)
    - Palmquist, Peter E. "A Question of Justice." The Humboldt Historian 40, no. 1 (1992): 20-24. (Box 50)
    - Palmquist, Peter E. "Regional Study Yields Biographical Dividends." AB Bookman's Weekly 89, no. 11 (1992): 1016-1020. (Box 50)
    - Johnson, Warren B. "Overland from Eureka to Massachusetts in 1882 'with a horse, carriage, cow and dog. '" Introduction by Peter E. Palmquist. The Humboldt Historian 40, no. 3 (1992): 14-20. (Box 50)
    - Palmquist, Peter E. "Pioneer Women Photographers in Nineteenth-Century California." California History 71, no. 1 (1992): 110-127. (Box 50)
    - Palmquist, Peter E. "California's 19th-Century Master of the Grand View." AB Bookman's Weekly 89, no. 5 (1992): 358-374. (Box 50)
    - Palmquist, Peter E. "Books by and About Women Photographers." AB Bookman's Weekly 91, no. 9 (1993): 845-856. (Box 50)
    - Palmquist, Peter E. Review of An Enterprising Life: Leonard Frank Photographs 1895-1944, by Cyril E. Leonoff. Forest & Conservation History 37, no. 2 (1993): 96-97. (Box 50)
    - Palmquist, Peter E. "Women Photographers and the American Indian." Rendezvous 28, nos. 1 and 2 (1992/1993): 121-150. (Box 50)
    - Palmquist, Peter E. "The Western Snapshot as Document." Journal of the West 33, no. 2 (1994): 28-35. (Box 50)
      Palmquist edited the issue and wrote an introduction.
    - Palmquist, Peter. "Ambitious Photographer Helped Promote NWP's 'Gap': Wild Hikes Before the Golden Spike." The Humboldt Historian 43, no. 4 (1995): 9-12. (Box 50)
    - The Pioneer: The Newsletter of the Society of California Pioneers 19, no. 16 (1995): 9. (Box 50)
    - Palmquist, Peter E. "Asian American Photographers on the Pacific Frontier, 1850-1930" and "Preliminary Checklist of Asian and Asian American Photographers and Related Trades, Active in California/Oregon/Washington, 1850-1930." In With New Eyes: Toward an Asian American Art History in the West, edited by Irene Poon Andersen, Mark Johnson, Dawn Nakanishi, and Diane Tani (San Francisco, California: College of Creative Arts, Art Department. Gallery, 1995), 15-21.. (Box 50)
    - Palmquist, Peter E. "Carleton E. Watkins: Master of the 'Grand View. '" The Argonaut: Journal of the San Francisco Historical Society 6, no. 2 (1995/1996): 4-32. (Box 50)
    - Palmquist, Peter. "Neil Hulbert – A Prince of Photojournalism." The Humboldt Historian 44, no. 4 (1996): 20-25. (Box 50)
    - Palmquist, Peter E. "Discovering Yosemite." Timeline 14, no. 3 (1997): 40-54. (Box 50)
    - Palmquist, Peter E. "Daguerre's Legacy." Bancroftiana: Newsletter of the Friends of the Bancroft Library, Fall (1997): 8-9. (Box 51)
    - Palmquist, Peter E. "Robert H. Vance: Pioneer Photographer." The Argonaut: Journal of the San Francisco Historical Society 8, no. 1 (1997): 4-35. (Box 51)
    - Gihon, Thomas. "An Incident at Gold Bluff." Introduction by Peter Palmquist. The Humboldt Historian 45, no. 1 (1997): 10-21. (Box 51)
    - Palmquist, Peter E., and Randall W. Law. Celebrating 50: A Keepsake Published in Commemoration of the Fiftieth Anniversary of the Humboldt County Historical Society, 1947-1997. (Eureka, California: Humboldt County Historical Society, 1997). (Box 51)
    - Palmquist, Peter E. A Wide Angle on "Photography and the Old West" (San Francisco, California: California Council for the Humanities, 1998). (Box 51)
      Exhibition brochure for exhibition, Photography and the Old West, produced and toured by ExhibitsUSA.
    - Palmquist, Peter E. "Asian Photographers in San Francisco 1850-1930." The Argonaut: Journal of the San Francisco Historical Society 9, no. 2 (1998): 86-91. (Box 51)
    - Palmquist, Peter E. "The Ubiquitous Tintype." The Pioneer: The Journal of the Society of California Pioneers 22, no. 1 (1999): 6-10. (Box 51)
    - Palmquist, Peter. "William E. Dassonville, California Photographer." American Art Review 12, no. 6 (2000): 184-189. (Box 51)
    - Humboldt County Historical Society. 41st Annual Luncheon and Program (Eureka, California: Humboldt County Historical Society, 2001). (Box 51)
      Program for an event featuring Palmquist as the guest speaker.
    - "Gathering Nuts: Images of and by Frederick C. Coombs (1803-1874) from the Peter E. Palmquist Collection." The Daguerreian Society Newsletter 13, no. 3 (2001): 13-21. (Box 51)
    - Moriarty, Jocelyn S., and Peter E. Palmquist. Abbie E. Cardozo: Portraits, Ferndale, California, 1895-1905 (Arcata, California: Women in Photography International Archive, 2002). (Box 51)
    - Doran, Bob. "A Photographer's Obsession." North Coast Journal, January 24, 2002. (Box 51)
    - "Remembering Peter E. Palmquist, 1936-2003." Stereo World 29, no. 3 (2002-2003): 24-30. (Box 51)
    - Hirsch, Robert. "Peter Eric Palmquist: Independent Photographic Historian, 1936-2003." Society for Photographic Education Members' Newsletter (2003): 1-3 (Box 51)
    - "Peter Palmquist." Bancroftiana: Newsletter of the Friends of the Bancroft Library no. 122 (2003): 14. (Box 51)
    - Dinsmore, Grant. Review of Photographers: A Sourcebook for Historical Research, edited by Peter Palmquist. The Daguerreian Society Newsletter 15, no. 1 (2003): 8-9. (Box 51)
    - International Photography Hall of Fame & Museum, and Photographic Art and Science Foundation. International Photography Hall of Fame & Museum 19, no. 1 (2003): 7. (Box 51)
    - "In Memory, Peter Palmquist: Remembering the Man, the Photographer, and the Historian." The Humboldt Historian 51, no. 1 (2003): 7-8. (Box 51)
    - Ehrens, Susan. "Peter Palmquist Remembered." Black & White Magazine 5, no. 24 (2003): 34. (Box 51)
    - Palmquist, Peter E. Peter E. Palmquist, 1936-2003 (Eureka, California: Eureka Printing, 2003). (Box 51)
    - Oversize Publications
      Publications with dimensions larger than 8.5 by 14 inches and smaller than 14 by 18 inches.
      - Theater Arts Department, Humboldt State College. "Sequoia Masque" Folder (Arcata, California: Humboldt State College, 1964). (Box 52)
      - Theater Arts Department, Humboldt State College. Theater Arts Department (Arcata, California: Humboldt State College, 1964). (Box 52)
      - Life 68, no. 6 (1970). (Box 52)
      - Toon, Wallace. "An Inside Look at the Great Outdoors." San Francisco Sunday Examiner &Chronicle, May 18, 1980. (Box 52)
      - Linwood, Elliott. "Interview with Peter Palmquist." Photo Metro 9, 82 (1990): 30-31. (Box 52)
      - Palmquist, Peter E. "The California Indian in Three-Dimensional Photography." Journal of California and Great Basin Anthropology, 1, no. 1 (1979): 89-116., circa 1979 (Box 52)
        Photocopy of the original manuscript.
  - Publications about California Photographic History, 26 folders (Box 53)
    Publications collected on California photographic history, many of which duplicate other examples of publications in the collection, which Palmquist prepared for binding as "Miscellaneous Writings in California Photographic History."
  - Publicity
    Arranged choronologically.
    Volumes with promotional material and clippings related to presentations and publications by Palmquist and designated by him as "Photo-History Press Clippings."
    - 1973-1976 (Box 54)
    - 1977-1978 (Box 55)
    - 1979-1982 (Box 56)
    - 1983 (Box 57)
    - 1984-1985 (Box 58)
    - 1986 (Box 59)
    - 1987-1988 (Box 60)
    - 1989 (Box 61)
    - 1990 (Box 62)
  - Awards
    Awards earned by Palmquist for his publications.
    - National Stereoscopic Association, Edward B. Berkowitz Memorial Award, 1982-1983 (Box 63)
    - Photographic Historical Society of New England, Outstanding Lecture, 1988 May 1 (Box 63)
    - The Western History/Genealogy Department, Denver Public Library, Caroline Bancroft Western History Prize, 2001 (Box 63)
- Material for Publications and Exhibitions, 1901-2003; Series III; 17.7 linear feet (44 boxes)
  Material collected by Palmquist for publications and exhibitions, in the order in which those were published, as well as drafts of his writings. This subseries includes original primary source material and research copies, as well as works by others.
  Organized chronologically into eleven subseries for distinct publications and exhibitions, followed by four subseries for Miscellaneous Manuscripts, Drafts and Mock-ups, Unrealized Projects, and Works by Others.
  - "Yesterday's Photographs: Reflections of the Past"
    Material related to a two-volume work on photographers of Shasta County, 1850-1900, Peter E. Palmquist, "Yesterday's Photographs: Reflections of the Past," in The Covered Wagon, 1977-1978 (Redding, California: Shasta Historical Society, 1977-1978).
    - Timeline of photographers in Shasta County, circa 1977 (Box 64)
    - Mock-up of Part II, 1870-1900, circa 1977 (Box 64)
  - The Photographers of the Humboldt Bay Region
    Organized under five headings: Correspondence; Volume I. 1850-1865; Volume II. 1865-1870; Volume III. 1870-1875; Volume IV. 1875-1880; and Volume VI. 1880-1885.
    Material related to the multivolume series, Peter E. Palmquist and Lincoln Kilian, The Photographers of the Humboldt Bay Region (Arcata, California: P. E. Palmquist, 1985-1989).
    - Correspondence, 1985-1989, undated; 5 folders
      Letters to Palmquist chiefly ordering copies of the books.
      - Letters to Palmquist chiefly ordering copies of the books. (Box 65)
    - Volume I. 1850-1865
      - Outline (Box 65)
      - Cover mock-up and galleys (Box 65)
      - Mock-up, photocopy, circa 1985 (Box 65)
      - Galleys (Box 65)
      - Introduction (Box 65)
      - Chapter I (Box 65)
      - Chapter II (Box 65)
      - Chapter III (Box 65)
      - Appendix I (Box 65)
      - Appendix II (Box 65)
      - Appendix III (Box 65)
      - Appendix IV (Box 65)
      - Appendix V (Box 65)
      - Appendix VI (Box 65)
      - Appendix VII (Box 65)
      - Appendix VIII (Box 65)
      - Bibliography (Box 65)
    - Volume II. 1865-1870
      - Cover galleys (Box 65)
      - Introduction (Box 65)
      - Chapter I (Box 65)
      - Chapter II (Box 65)
      - Portfolio (Box 65)
      - Appendix I (Box 65)
      - Appendix II (Box 65)
      - Appendix III (Box 65)
      - Appendix IV (Box 65)
      - Appendix V (Box 65)
      - Bibliography (Box 65)
    - Volume III. 1870-1875
      - Introduction (Box 66)
      - Chapter I (Box 66)
      - Appendix II (Box 66)
      - Appendix III (Box 66)
      - Appendix IV (Box 66)
      - Appendix V (Box 66)
      - Bibliography (Box 66)
    - Volume IV. 1875-1880
      - Introduction (Box 66)
      - Chapter I (Box 66)
      - Chapter II, 2 folders (Box 66)
      - Chapter III (Box 66)
      - Appendix II (Box 66)
      - Appendix III (Box 66)
      - Appendix IV (Box 66)
      - Appendix V (Box 66)
    - Volume VI. 1880-1885
      - Chapter I (Box 66)
      - Appendix I (Box 66)
      - Appendix II (Box 66)
      - Appendix III (Box 66)
  - Shadowcatchers II: A Directory of Women in Photography, 1900-1920
    Mock-up for Peter E. Palmquist, Shadowcatchers II: A Directory of Women in California Photography 1900-1920 (Arcata, California: P. E. Palmquist, 1991).
    - Front Matter (Box 67)
    - A (Box 67)
    - B (Box 67)
    - C (Box 67)
    - D (Box 67)
    - E (Box 67)
    - F (Box 67)
    - G (Box 67)
    - H (Box 67)
    - I-K (Box 67)
    - L (Box 67)
    - M (Box 67)
    - N-O (Box 67)
    - P-Q (Box 67)
    - R (Box 67)
    - S (Box 67)
    - T-V (Box 67)
    - W-Z (Box 67)
    - Cross-index (Box 67)
  - To the American Indian: Reminiscences of a Yurok Woman
    Research related to Lucy Thompson, To the American Indian: Reminiscences of a Yurok Woman (Berkeley, California: Heyday Books in conjunction with P. E. Palmquist, 1991) and includes original primary material created by the family of Lucy Thompson.
    - Lucy Thompson, et. al. To The American Indian, collected notes as of September 1991, 1991 September; 1 volume (Box 68)
    - Allen, C. F., Pocket Township Plot Book (Box 69)
    - Unidentified author, letter to Milton J. Thompson (Box 69)
    - Beck, Lucia, letter to Lucy Thompson (Box 69)
    - Clipping from the The Evening Herald (Box 69)
    - Stewart, S. V., letter to "Mrs. White Elk" (Burtha Thompson), 1922 September 6 (Box 69)
    - Thompson, Alice, postcard to Lucy Thompson, 1913 October 2 (Box 69)
    - Thompson, Bertha, letter to Gabe E. Parker, 1922 September 20 (Box 69)
    - Thompson, Burtha, postcards to Lucy Thompson and Milton Thompson, 1909-1910 (Box 69)
    - Thompson, Burtha, "Old Black Jack," song (Box 69)
    - Thompson?, Eva, postcard to "Aunt Lucy" Thompson (Box 69)
    - Thompson, Milton J., "A Sketch of the Life and Ancestors of the Notorious Jimmy Donnelly.. .", 1909 November 8 (Box 69)
    - Thompson, Milton J., "The Truthful Story of Charly Salton Killing Jeff Baldwin.. .", 1911 September 30 (Box 69)
    - Thompson, Milton J., photograph of writing fragment (Box 69)
    - Thompson, Pearl F., postcard to Milton Thompson (Box 69)
    - Thompson, Thana and Dorothy Thompson, postcards to Lucy Thompson and Milton Thompson (Box 69)
    - White Elk, Chief, Application to the United States War Department for a certificate of identification, 1917 August (Box 69)
    - White Elk, Chief, postcard to Milton Thompson ("Dad") (Box 69)
    - White Elk, Chief, photographs of speaking events, 1918 (Box 69)
    - White Elk, Chief, family photographs, 1918-1923 (Box 69)
    - Photographs of American Indian ceremonies (Box 69)
    - Photographs of buildings and structures (Box 69)
    - Photograph and postcard of the Government Indian School, Sherman Institute, Riverside, California (Box 69)
    - Photographs of Lucy Thompson and family (Box 69)
    - Photographs of the Thompson family (Box 69)
    - Newspaper obituary for "Surgeon Jim" (Box 69)
    - Census data, newspaper articles, and notes regarding Lucy Thompson research (Box 69)
    - Photocopies of Thompson family correspondence and photographs (Box 69)
    - Correspondence with Malcolm Margolin, 1992 (Box 69)
    - Correspondence with Darlene Jay Buckley (Box 69)
    - Oversize Material
      Material larger than 8.5 by 14 inches and smaller than 14 by 18 inches.
      - Abstract Map of Humboldt County showing property rights (Box 70)
      - "A blackberrying party" (Box 70)
      - Map of Humboldt County showing wagon roads, trails, and patented land with notes (Box 70)
      - Topographical map of Humboldt County, 1901 (Box 70)
      - Map of Blue Creek, Humboldt County, possibly showing land ownership (Box 70)
  - The West, Then and Now
    Material related to an issue, "The West, Then and Now," of The Journal of the West in April 1994, for which Palmquist served as the guest editor.
    - Miller, Kathleen L., "The Temple Block"
      - Correspondence and notes (Box 71)
      - Drafts, 1993; 2 folders (Box 71)
      - Illustrations, 2 folders (Box 71)
  - With New Eyes: Toward an Asian American Art History of the West
    Material related to the exhibition With New Eyes: Toward an Asian American Art History of the West at the Fine Arts Gallery of San Francisco State University, September 24, 1995, to October 26, 1995.
    - Preliminary checklist of Asian-American Photographers active in California 1850-1920 (Box 72)
    - Asian photographers (Box 72)
    - Preliminary checklist, 1850-1930, 2 folders (Box 72)
    - Preliminary checklist, 1995 July, annotations by Mariko Yabe (Box 72)
    - Asian Photographers on the Pacific Frontier, 1850-1930, circa 1995 (Box 72)
    - With New Eyes: Toward an Asian American Art History of the West, exhibit, 1995 (Box 72)
    - With New Eyes: Toward an Asian American Art History of the West, exhibit catalog, 1995 (Box 72)
    - In Splendid Detail, 2001 (Box 72)
    - Asian photographers in the Argonaut, 1998 (Box 72)
  - Perpetual Mirage: Photographic Narratives of the Desert West
    Material related to the exhibition, Perpetual Mirage: Photographic Narratives of the Desert West, at the Whitney Museum of American Art, New York, in 1996.
    - Exhibition proposal (Box 73)
    - Draft essays for the exhibition catalog (Box 73)
    - Palmquist, Peter E., "Waterless Mountain," draft (Box 73)
  - Faith of Fools: A Journal of the Klondike Gold Rush
    Material related to the diary and photographs by William H. Shape (1867-1960), which documents a trip to Alaska, August 1897 to October 1898, which Palmquist edited and published as William Shape, Faith of Fools: A Journal of the Klondike Gold Rush (Pullman, Washington: Washington State Univ. Press, 1998).
    - Photocopy of the diary, 5 folders (Box 74)
    - List of photographs (Box 74)
    - Maps (Box 74)
    - Typescripts of the diary, 2 folders (Box 74)
    - Galleys, 2 folders (Box 74)
  - Pioneer Photographers of the Far West: A Biographical Dictionary, 1840-1865
    Organized under two headings: Research Material and Drafts.
    Material related to Peter E. Palmquist and Thomas R. Kailbourn, Pioneer Photographers of the Far West: A Biographical Dictionary, 1840-1865 (Stanford, California: Stanford University Press, 2000).
    - Research Material
      - Kerr, Joan, The Dictionary of Australian Artists: Painters, Sketchers, Photographers and Engravers to 1870 (Melbourne: Oxford University Press), 1992 (Box 75)
        The Dictionary of Australian Artists served as a model for Pioneer Photographers of the Far West: A Biographical Dictionary, 1840-1865
      - City Directories
        - San Francisco Directory, 1850 (Box 75)
        - Marin County Directory, 1946-1947 (Box 75)
      - United States Censuses
        - United States Census, California, 1850 (Box 75)
        - United States Census, California, 1852 (Box 75)
        - United States Census, California, 1860 (Box 75)
        - United States Census, California, 1870 (Box 75)
        - United States Census, California, 1920, 2 folders (Box 75)
    - Drafts
      - Preliminary draft (Box 76)
      - Draft, circa 1998; 16 folders (Box 76)
      - Draft illustrations
        - A (Box 77)
        - B (Box 77)
        - C (Box 77)
        - D (Box 77)
        - E (Box 77)
        - F (Box 77)
        - G (Box 77)
        - H (Box 77)
        - I (Box 77)
        - J (Box 77)
        - K (Box 77)
        - L (Box 77)
        - M (Box 77)
        - N (Box 77)
        - O (Box 77)
        - P (Box 77)
        - R (Box 77)
        - S (Box 77)
        - T (Box 77)
        - V (Box 77)
        - W (Box 77)
        - Z (Box 77)
        - Unidentified photographers, 2 folders (Box 77)
  - Women Photographers in the Collection of the Women in Photography International Archive
    Photocopy of a draft of Peter E. Palmquist, Women Photographers in the Collection of the Women in Photography International Archive, as of January 1, 2003: Biographical and Resource Index, A-Z (Arcata, California: Women in Photography International Archive, 2003)
    - Front Matter, 2003 (Box 78)
    - A, 2003 (Box 78)
    - B, 2003 (Box 78)
    - C, 2003 (Box 78)
    - D-E, 2003 (Box 78)
    - F-G, 2003 (Box 78)
    - H-K, 2003 (Box 78)
    - L-N, 2003 (Box 78)
    - O-R, 2003 (Box 78)
    - S-T, 2003 (Box 78)
    - U-Z, 2003 (Box 78)
  - Pioneer Photographers from the Mississippi to the Continental Divide: A Biographical Dictionary, 1839-1865
    Organized under six headings: Research Material, Biographical Material, Geographical Research, Drafts, Illustrations, and Correspondence.
    Material for Peter E. Palmquist and Thomas R. Kailbourn, Pioneer Photographers from the Mississippi to the Continental Divide: A Biographical Dictionary, 1839-1865 (Stanford, California: Stanford University Press, 2005).
    - General Research Material
      - Newspaper research, 2 folders (Box 79A)
        Lists of newspapers to read for biographical information about photographers,
      - City directories for New Orleans, 1853-1856, 1860, 2 folders (Box 79A)
      - Log of photographers, 1998 December 20; 2 folders (Box 79A)
    - Biographical Material
      - Photographers in Mississippi and Texas (Box 79A)
      - Barret, J. J. (Box 79A)
      - Blakey, R. E. (Box 79A)
      - Croucher, J. H. (Box 79A)
      - F. H. Clark & Co. (Box 79A)
      - Forsyth, William (Box 79A)
      - Haines, W. C. (Box 79A)
      - Housel, C. J. (Box 79A)
      - Kenyon, O. A. (Box 79A)
      - Parrott (Box 79A)
      - Sacan, F. (Box 79A)
      - Simmons, J. S. (Box 79A)
    - Geographical Research
      Manuscript lists of photographers in selected states and territories, as well as Mexico and Canada, circa 1850-1880, probably made by an assistant.
      - Arkansas (Box 79A)
      - Iowa (Box 79A)
      - Kansas (Box 79A)
      - Louisiana (Box 79A)
      - Minnesota (Box 79A)
      - Missouri (Box 79A)
      - Nebraska (Box 79A)
      - North Dakota (Box 79A)
      - Oklahoma (Box 79A)
      - South Dakota (Box 79A)
      - Texas (Box 79A)
      - Prairie Canada (Box 79A)
      - Mexico (Box 79A)
      - Women photographers (Box 79A)
      - Artists (Box 79A)
      - Minnesota (Box 79A)
    - Drafts
      - Computer files name log (Box 79B)
      - Appendix 5: Geographical Distribution of Workers (Box 79B)
      - Rejects (Box 79B)
    - Illustrations
      - Getty (Box 79B)
      - Minnesota Historical Society (Box 79B)
      - Schaeffer, Willie (Box 79B)
      - Illustrations (Box 79B)
      - Captions, 2003 January-March 10, undated; 4 folders (Box 79B)
      - Figures to be copied (Box 79B)
      - Permissions, 2003 January 22-February 12; 2 folders (Box 79B)
    - Correspondence
      - Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library (Box 79B)
      - Jones, Larry (Box 79B)
      - Kailbourn, Thomas (Box 79B)
      - Nathanson, Philip D. (Box 79B)
      - University of Oklahoma Press (Box 79B)
      - Van Zante, Gary (Box 79B)
      - Victoria Mansion (Box 79B)
  - Miscellaneous Manuscripts
    Volumes with drafts of articles written by Palmquist, 1973-1989, and designated by him as "Miscellaneous Manuscripts."
    - Volume 1, 1973-1989 (Box 80)
      Volume includes:
      "Readings in Western Photographic History"
      "Alfred A. Hart and the Illustrated Traveler's Map of the Central Pacific Railroad"
      "[Big, Bigger and Biggest]"
      "Bridging the Gap in Pictures: The NWP Photographs of Edwin R. Freeman 1910-1914"
      "California's Amazing Collector - - Lester Silva"
      "The California Indian in Three- Dimensional Photography "
      "Don Rafael Ordonez Castro: A Spanish Photographer Captures California's Giant Redwood Trees for Spain"
      "Distinguishing Apples from Oranges"
      "Imagemakers of the Modoc War -- Louis Heller and Eadweard Muybridge"
      "The Image of Music in the West"
      "The Indomitable Mrs. Withington, or, How I Use My Skirt for a Darktent"
    - Volume 2, 1973-1989 (Box 81)
      "John Oliver Welsh"
      "Mirror of Our Conscience: A Brief Look at Our Surviving Photographic Documents of California Indians Before 1860"
      "[Miscellaneous topics, vignettes, etc.]"
      "Odyssey of a Cameraman"
      "Photographers in Petticoats"
      "The Photographers of Humboldt Bay"
      "Photographic Archeology: A Case for Regional Research"
      "Photographic Caricature as Seen in Harper's New Monthly Magazine "
      "Photographing San Francisco's Opium Fiends"
      "Photographing the Modoc Indian War: Louis Heller vs. Eadweard Muybridge"
      "Photographing the Thousand Year Flood"
    - Volume 3, 1973-1989 (Box 82)
      "Photography in Medicine"
      "The Ubiquitous Western Tintype"
      "The Roberts Collection of California Indian Photographs"